{
  "reference_number": "12318",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Long-Lived Gases and Stabilised Short-Lived Gases - Long-lived gases to net zero by 2050 while also stabilising short-lived gases",
      "answer_index": 12,
      "notes": "Support the concept of treating short lived gases (methane from ruminants) differently from long lived GHG, as long the global\n temperature increase is below agreed international targets. If global temperatures are less than 2 degrees then stabilising methane\n\n emissions (to reduce further temperature increases) is sufficient. However as we get closer to the 2 degree threshold then the size\n of temperature increase contributed by methane emissions needs to decrease and be accounted for"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions (including from new forest planting) and using some emissions reductions from overseas (international carbon units) that have strong environmental safeguards",
      "answer_index": 2,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "• Despite NZ being a small country and having a very small impact on total global GHG emissions, we should still participate in\n\nreducing emissions and playing our part internationally. Possibly our strongest contribution could be demonstrating a how a country\ncan transition to a carbon neutral economy • Support the establishment of a climate commission • Climate change commission\n\nshould be a decision making group to take our response to climate change out of the political arena. • New Zealand’s economy by\n2050 should be shaped by economic activity that has an emissions profile that reflects New Zealand’s equitable contribution on a\n\nworld wide scale, to fit within a 2 degree change. Any climate change policy should seek to achieve this. • Any economic\nincentives/penalties should reflect the cost/benefit of the changed activity and be designed to shift NZ’s economy to fully account for\n\nthe effect of GHG emissions. • Support the concept of treating short lived gases (methane from ruminants) differently from long lived\nGHG, as long the global temperature increase is below agreed international targets. If global temperatures are less than 2 degrees\nthen stabilising methane emissions (to reduce further temperature increases) is sufficient. However as we get closer to the 2 degree\n\nthreshold then the size of temperature increase contributed by methane emissions needs to decrease and this may mean that the\nshort term GHG emissions that is emitted from our agriculture sector needs to decrease as we get closer to the 2 degree threshold.\n\n• In the interim (while below the 2 degree threshold) the amount of short lived GHG that a farmer can emit should be linked to area of\nthe farm. It should be net emissions after taking account of any sequestration taking place on the farm. • Support idea of emission\n\nbudgets. This set short term targets and allows monitoring progress against them. • 2050 target should be able to be changed if\ncircumstances change."
    }
  ]
}
